Joseph Nkumah

25 Adeyinka Adebayo Street, Apo Legislative Quarters, Abuja.
Mobile Number: 08024449872
Whatsapp Number: 08152667699
Email: josephnkumah97@gmail.com

Profile

A dedicated and enthusiastic MSc graduate in Sports Performance Analysis (Analytics). With significant employment and voluntary experience. I can work to a very high standard using my own initiative or as part of the team. Ability to communicate with a variety of people and manage them with my leadership skills.

Education & Qualifications

Cardiff Metropolitan University, Wales

2017-2019

MSc Sports Performance Analysis (Analytics)

- Developed the ability to integrate software systems with databases.
- Gained knowledge of software system principles.
- Development of writing skills and methodologies through reporting research essays.
- Used sport professional software Nacsport and Sport code to collect sport data for analysis.
- Developed programs and analyzed data using MATLAB.
- Utilized Excel and Tableau for visualization.
- Used SPSS to develop models and predict outcomes.
- Used UCINET and SOCNETV to conduct social network analysis experiments.
- Dissertation project topic: Network Analysis of the top four teams in the English Premier League.

Bingham University, Nigeria

2011-2015

BSc Computer Science (2.1)

- Dissertation topic: Web Development of a School Football Team.
- Developed the ability to create programs with programming languages such as QBasic, Java and C++.
- Designed and managed websites using HTML, PHP, and MySQL.

Employment

Web Developer

March 2021-Present

First Samone International/Luday AB

- Develop web based PHP Laravel applications.
- Develop cross-platform responsive front-end websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Bootstrap.
- Host web applications on Amazon Web Services.
- Use package managers such as Composer and NPM.
- Use version control through git and BitBucket.

.

Implement Agile method to work as a team to develop web and mobile solutions for customers.

Web/Software Development Instructor(Part-time)

March 2021- May 2021

- El Academy
- Train students on Python programming language.
- Prepare assessments for improving students' knowledge.
- Relay knowledge of modern programming practices such as Object Oriented Programming (OOP).
- Teach programming languages such as HTML, CSS and Javascript.

Web/Software Development Instructor El Academy

November 2020-January 2021

- Training and preparing students for internship in El Academy.
- Solve complex problems using Python programming language.
- Relay knowledge of front end and back end development tools to develop individuals in web development.
- Teach programming languages such as HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP and Python to students and develop or improve their programming skills.

Data Scientist (Intern)

July 2020-August 2020

Hash Analytic, United Kingdom.

- Manage master data set, develop reports, and troubleshoot data issues.
- Remote work with data science professionals to understand data, develop models and predict outcomes.
- Analysis of data to answer complicated questions from data provided.
- Using Python and Tableau to visualize data for excellent presentation.
- Using Machine Learning techniques to train and test models for best fit.

Data Scientist (Intern)

June 2020-September 2020

DataLab, Nigeria.

- Collected, interpreted & analyzed data to generate insights and forecast based on trends.
- Built algorithms, design experiments, and analyze data to drive optimization and improvement of product development, marketing techniques, and business strategies.
- Assessed the effectiveness and accuracy of new data sources and data gathering techniques.
- Used machine learning tools, predictive modeling, and statistical techniques to produce solutions to problems and optimize business outcomes.
- Identified patterns and trends in data sets.

Software Programmer (Intern)

January 2020-April 2020

NanoMatriX, Hong Kong.

- Assisted in designing and developing high-quality interactive UI for mobile and desktop users.
- Assisted in the developing web and mobile applications.
- Communicated with designers and sales to meet content and functional requirements.
- Program, application testing and implementation.
- Applied and improved best practices in coding and documentation for quality assurance.
- Prepared system documentation and conduct program performance tests to assure optimal
- performance across multiple browsers and operating systems.
- Used AWS services to develop models, train data and carry out deployment.

Assistant lecturer 2015-2016

Federal College of Education (Technical), Nigeria.

- Awarded the Certificate of National Youth Service Corps (NYSC).
- Served as assistant lecturer and taught computer science to students.
- Assisted colleagues with the preparation of test and examination papers.
- Invigilated examinations and was given the responsibility of marking assignments, tests and examination scripts.
- Assisted the Computer Science Head of Department with projects for the faculty.

Equipment Supervisor

2014

Capital FM, 92.9, Nigeria

- A six-month internship at a radio station in my third year of university.
- Given responsibility to supervise equipment used for transmitting signals.
- Assisted colleagues in developing a website for the radio station.

Professional Training

El Academy September 2020-November 2020

Python Programming Language

Bincom Academy September 2020-October 2020

Licenses and Certificates

Cousera - IBM June 2020

Data Analysis with Python

Digital Marketing

LinkedIn August 2020

HTML Essential Training No Expiration Date

LinkedIn August 2020

CSS Essential Training No Expiration Date

LinkedIn August 2020

Marketing Foundations: Automation

No Expiration Date

LinkedIn August 2020

Marketing Tools: Automation

No Expiration Date

LinkedIn August 2020

SEO Foundations No Expiration Date

LinkedIn August 2020

Shopify Essential Training No Expiration Date

Google August 2020

Google Analytics for Beginners

Expires August 2023

Google August 2020

Advanced Google Analytics Expires August 2023

Skills

Industry Knowledge

- Research
- Data Analysis
- Data Modeling
- Data Visualization
- Brand Management
- Digital Marketing
- Search Engine Optimization (SEO)
- Machine Learning
- E-commerce
- Web Development
- Web Design

Tools and Technologies

- Microsoft PowerPoint
- MATLAB

- SPSS
- Microsoft Excel
- Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- AWS SageMaker
- WordPress
- Python (Programming Language)
- Google Analytics
- ActiveCampaign
- HubSpot
- MailChimp
- Tableau
- Shopify
- HTML
- Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)
- JavaScript
- Bootstrap
- PHP (Programming Language)
- Laravel

Interpersonal Skills

- Teamwork
- Leadership

Other Skills

- Data Analytics
- Social Network Analysis
- UCINET
- Linear Regression
- Correlation Analysis
- Small Business Marketing
- Marketing Automation
- Sports data analytics
- Amazon Fraud Detector

Voluntary Work

Head Coach 2017-2019

Cardiff Metropolitan University International Football Team, Wales

- Developed the ability to be a leader as I organize training schedules and prepare the team for games.
- Given the responsibility to coach the International football team of Cardiff Metropolitan University.
- Improvised training drills and programs to aid the team's development.
- Motivated players to improve individually and as a team.

References available on request.